IHOR TSELUIKO

+(1)424-2895-780 | tseluyko.igor@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tseluiko

Los Angeles, California, 90025

Java Backend Software Engineer

• **Dynamic software engineer offering 5 years** of experience developing high-loaded, mission-critical projects. Skilled in backend development lifecycle, NoSql solutions; Has a lot of experience in multithreaded applications. Provides clean estimations to project management, working on the research, design, development, documentation, testing and rollout of enterprise applications.

SUMMARY

Languages: Java 8(advanced), Scala (beginner), Bash (expert), T-SQL (expert) **Development Tools, Libraries, Frameworks:** Spring Data, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring JDBC, Spring AOP, Intellij IDEA, jvisualvm, Eclipse MAT, Nginx, Zabbix, Sonar, Hudson, Maven, JUnit, Apache Commons, Google Guava, Cucumber, Mockito, Git, Svn, Ant

Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Waterfall

Systems: Unix, Windows

Databases: Sybase, Oracle, PostgreSQL

NoSQL: Hbase, Redis, Mongodb

EXPERIENCE

GlobalLogic (Poland): Bottomline, Paymode-X (February 2017 – May 2017)

Software Engineer

- Stored procedures development (Oracle). SQL queries development as well as SQL performance testing, improving.
- Huge security patch for the product in order to pass financial security code of conduct. Algorithms of encryption/decryption users data. Migration to java 8. Design and coding sessions with juniors.

EPAM Systems (Poland): GK Software (September 2016 – February 2017)

Software Engineer

- New SOAP webservice endpoints development.
- Tons of refactoring made on old legacy project (since 2004): Slowly moving to newer java version, patterns and best practices implemented. KISS, SOLID. Improved test coverage.
- Developing and improving user experience of product usage. (POS-terminals).
 Adjusting screens, menus, buttons with functionality from backend side. Database queries performance tuning, jvm tuning, memory leaks investigating.

EPAM Systems (Poland): CME-SGE (June 2015 - September 2016)

Software Engineer

 Design and development of highloaded multithreaded gateway between two exchanges: Chicago vs Shanghai. Integration into inner CME systems with multiple security standards. • Unit and integration tests scenarios, implementation. Inner cache recovery system development (similar to Redis Sentinel)

PrivatBank (Ukraine): CRM system (October 2013 – May 2015)

Software Engineer

- Migration of queues from RDB(Sybase) to RabbitMq. Design of queues, exchanges, routing keys. Reduced Sybase License budget (\$1M per 1 cpu core) while increasing service levels and improving product stability.
- Database migration from RDB(Sybase ~60Tb) to NoSql(Hbase). Decreased monthly error-by-timeout rates to all-time lows (from 1.5% to 0.01%). Reduced request latency time from 200ms to 50ms.
- MongoDb. Design collection, indexes, find criteria for storing 250 millions of expired unordered data.
- Horizontal scaling of fast-growing project. Scaled to multiple instances (load balancer - nginx, cache layer - redis). Using cache fault-tolerance redis-sentinel system.
- Resolving complex bugs with help of profiling(jvisualVM) and Eclipse MAT tools.
- Mail worker redesigned on multithreaded architecture without horizontal scaling, increased throughput from 200k to 1M per day.

PrivatBank (Ukraine): Internet banking system (August 2012 - October 2013)

Software Engineer

- Authorization support. QR-code, OTP, inner bank authorization systems. Took part in creating of new type of authorization: via google-glass; New REST Api endpoints development.
- Automatize sybase_iq backup process. Develop bash scripts to automatize backup between node of servers and different sybase iq versions.
- Redesign of authorization architecture, new more secured QR-code algorithm.
 Logging systems performance tuning, migration from Servlets API to Spring framework.

EDUCATION

Ukraine, DNU: BS in Economical Cybernetics.